你觉得哪个婚礼套餐好
So, what package are you thinking?
这套餐有音乐跟鲜花呢
Mm, this one comes with music and flowers.
而且还能在网上直播我们的婚礼
Oh, they even stream the whole thing live on the Internet.
我们直播了干嘛
Why would we want that?
因为世上还有许多漂亮的金发妹
'Cause there's a lot of gorgeous blondes out there
不信自己能有幸找到一个四眼短腿科学家
who don't believe they can land a short, nearsighted scientist.
让她们看到还有希望嘛
Let's give them hope.
随便  网上直播就直播吧
Whatever. Put us on the Internet.
我从小就"梦想"自己的婚礼有个留言区
I've always wanted a wedding with a comment section.
如果你不想  我们可以以后再结
I-If you're not into this, we can do it another time.
不  不  我想结婚
No. No, I want to.
这事我们已经拖得太久了
Look, we've put this off long enough.
现在就做吧
Let's do it.
我们第一次"睡"时  你也说现在就"做"吧
That's exactly what you said the first time we slept together.
抱歉
Oh, excuse me.
谢尔顿
Sheldon.
莱纳德  你结完婚了吗
Leonard, have you gotten married yet?
还没  怎么了
No. Why?
-那就好  别结  -为什么不行
- Good. Don't do it! - Why not?
我刚发现了重要的新资讯
Some important new information has come to light.
女人最坏了
Women are the worst.
我本以为就像被纸割到手  但我错了
I thought it was paper cuts, but I was wrong.
从没有一张纸比女人割我还深
No piece of paper ever cut me this deep.
又怎么啦
What happened now?
艾米跟我分手了
Amy has ended our relationship.
不是吧  真的吗
Oh, no. Seriously?
发生什么事了
What's going on?
艾米甩了谢尔顿
Amy broke up with Sheldon.
真的吗
She did?
佩妮泪崩了吗
Is Penny crying?
没有
No.
她当然不会哭啦
No, of course not.
女人巴不得看我们受折磨
They thrive on our suffering.
兄弟  我很遗憾
Buddy, I-I'm so sorry.
我能为你做点什么吗
Is there anything I can do?
能  以后我再说我要跟女生交往
Yes. If I ever talk about going out with a girl again,
你就对我翻白眼
roll your eyes at me
就像我听到你说蠢话时的那样
like I do to you when you say dumb things.
行  谢尔顿
Sheldon, uh, o-okay,
虽然艾米让你难过了
just because you're going through this with Amy
但并不代表所有女人都很坏
doesn't mean that all women are bad.
呵呵
Whatever.
我刚听说你跟谢尔顿的事  你还好吗
Hey, I just heard about you and Sheldon. Are you okay?
不太好
Not really.
你能来陪我吗
Can you come over?
我现在在赌城
Uh, actually I'm in Vegas.
我跟莱纳德准备要结婚了
Leonard and I are about to get married.
等等
Hold on.
你们结婚居然没邀请我
You're getting married and you didn't invite me?
我们只是一时心血来潮
Well, it was kind of a spur-of-the-moment thing.
希望我能从这里接到你的捧花啊
Hope I can catch the bouquet from here.
艾米  别这样嘛
Amy, don't be like that.
为什么我听到有人说艾米的名字
Why did I just hear Amy's name?
佩妮在跟她通电话
Penny's on the phone with her.
她有提到我吗
Did she say anything about me?
算了  我才不在乎
Never mind. I don't care.
如果你在乎  你可以问清楚告诉我
Well, if you care, you can find out and tell me.
但你发现我压根不在乎时  别太惊讶哦
Just don't be shocked when you find out that I don't care.
你别激动好吗
Okay, will you relax?
你才没错过什么大事
You're not missing anything special.
怎么说话呢
Hey.
她心情不好嘛
She's upset.
婚礼肯定会很赞
Look, it's gonna be a great wedding.
瞧你一身小正装
Look at you in your little suit.
艾米心情不好是因为我吗
Amy's upset? Is it about me?
不是  我想是因为我们私奔来结婚
No, I think it's because we're eloping.
你的婚礼让她难受了吗
Your marriage is causing her pain?
太好了  我收回之前的话
Yeah, great, I take it back.
快去结婚吧  爱情万岁
Go ahead and do it. Yay for love!
翻译：爱情万岁谢尔赛  真爱无敌妮妮猫
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h猫中有个猴子王  窗里窗外赛猫党
你好
Hello.
你来这里干嘛
What are you doing here?
我们最后一次通话时  你说你需要时间冷静
When last we spoke, you said you needed time.
这才过了11个小时
Well, it's only been 11 hours.
《指环王》三部曲也差不多11小时
The Lord of the Rings trilogy was nearly 11 hours.
我让你看完它们  你说这11小时如永恒
I made you watch that, you said it was an eternity.
谢尔顿  等我想跟你谈会通知你的
Sheldon, when I'm ready to talk, I'll let you know.
好吧
Very well.
你要出门呀
You seem to be headed somewhere.
我能陪你走出去吗
May I walk with you?
行
Sure.
真庆幸我们又"一起出去"了
Boy, I'm glad we're going out again.
我们不是复合
We're not back together.
为什么
Why?
有新欢了吗
Is there someone else?
一逮到机会
Just couldn't wait for that first notch
就等不及要"开荤"了是吧
on your bedpost, could you?
如果你一定要问
If you must know,
我是要去霍华德与伯纳黛特家
I'm going to Howard and Bernadette's
一起看婚礼直播
to watch the wedding.
你要带哪个男人去
And who's this guy you're taking?
没有要带男人
There's no guy!
你要形单影只的去参加婚礼吗
Oh, you're going to a wedding alone?
好惨呐
That's sad.
我才不会形单影只
I'm not gonna be alone.
我的小伙伴们也会在
I'll be with my friends.
"你的"小伙伴们吗
Your friends?
他们是我的小伙伴吧
Well, I think you mean my friends.
而且为什么没人邀请我啊
And why wasn't I invited to this?
或许是因为我们两个同时在场
Maybe because the two of us being there
会让他们觉得很尴尬吧
would make them feel awkward.
我们让所有人感到尴尬
We make everyone feel awkward.
这是我们的招牌啊
That's our thing!
前面的人可能耽误了
They're running a little behind.
-应该很快就到我们了  -好的
- Should be pretty soon. - Okay.
如果你饿了  隔壁那家脱衣舞厅
Hey, if you're hungry, there's a breakfast buffet
有自助早餐
at the strip club next door.
多谢  但我不喜欢煎蛋上有闪粉
Thanks, but I don't like glitter on my scrambled eggs.
早餐应该不是脱衣舞娘做的吧  但没关系
I don't think the strippers prepare the meal, but okay.
虽然这跟我想象中的也不一样
Look, it-it's not how I pictured it either,
但我很高兴我们要结婚了
but I'm still glad we're doing it.
我也是
Me, too.
-你确定吗  -确定
- You sure? - Yes.
你保证车里的谈话不会影响到你吗
And you promise you're okay with everything from the car?
老天  你能不能别一个劲地提这茬
Oh, my God, would you stop bringing it up?
你说得对  对不起
You're right. I'm sorry.
我们还有一辈子的时间
We have the rest of our lives
可以慢慢翻旧账  再大吵一架
to dredge stuff up from the past and fight about it.
你觉得怎么样
So what do you think?
我们要不要去隔壁吃一口
Should we run next door and grab a bite?
万一叫到我们怎么办
What if they call our names?
别担心  他们给了我震动叫号器
Oh, don't worry. They gave me this vibrating coaster.
哇  真是犹如"童话"一般
Oh, and the fairy tale continues.
感谢你们收留我
Thank you for doing this.
别客气
Our pleasure.
你心情还好吗
You feeling okay?
我们在一起这么久
We were together for so long,
老实说  我都不知道现在是什么心情
I honestly don't know what I'm feeling.
可以理解
Well, that's understandable.
因为你忘了这种心情叫"快乐"
You forgot. It's called "happy."
霍华德
Howard.
我又没说什么不好的话
I'm not saying anything bad.
她爱上了囚禁自己的变态
Just that she was in love with her captor
结果福至心灵逃出了他阴暗又疯狂的地牢
and somehow managed to escape from his dark and crazy dungeon.
我知道你现在的感受
I know what you're going through.
我前一次分手也非常不好受
My-my last breakup was pretty tough.
是吗  那女孩叫什么
Oh. What was her name?
拜托  这可是真事
Hey, it's a true story.
不需要这么逼问我细节吧
I don't need the third degree.
要人命啊  谢尔顿  你在干嘛
For God's sake, Sheldon, what are you doing?
我不想进去
I didn't want to come in.
有人说我会让大家觉得尴尬
I was told it would make everyone feel uncomfortable.
所以我就在外面待着
So I'll just stay out here
假装我不需要上洗手间
and pretend that I don't have to go to the bathroom.
霍华德  想想办法
Howard, do something.
交给我吧
I'm on it.
谢尔顿  你来这也不会让事情产生转机
Sheldon, you being here might not be making things better.
我明白
I see.
所以你们邀请大家  唯独漏了我吗
And is that why everybody was invited but me?
他们没有邀请大家不邀请你啊
They didn't invite everybody but you.
伯纳黛特邀请我
Bernadette invited me,
斯尔图特本来就住这里
and Stuart lives here.
谁想吃刚出炉的肉桂卷啊
Who wants hot cinnamon rolls?
一听到音乐  你们就可以往前走了
So, when you hear the music, that's your cue.
有问题吗
Any questions?
我们买的那个套餐
Oh, the package that we paid for
写着走道上会铺满玫瑰花瓣
said the aisle was supposed to be strewn with rose petals.
玫瑰花瓣呢
Where are the rose petals?!
没了
We're out!
算了  没事
You know what? It's fine.
我们可以用厕所里的干花瓣
We can use the potpourri from the bathroom!
真的不需要了
Really, we're good.
对  结婚才是重点
Yup, just want to get married.
-对  -那就好
- Yeah. - Great.
我在圣坛上等你们
I'll see you two up there.
-这一刻终于来了  -我知道
- This is it. - I know.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
干花瓣还要不要了
Was that a yes or no on the potpourri?!
-不要了  -谢谢
- No, thank you! - We're good!
拉杰  你脑中肯定在想
Raj, you're probably wondering
为什么我和艾米不秀恩爱了
why Amy and I aren't showing any affection to one another.
这事都没挤进我脑海中的前十
Didn't even crack the top ten.
你应该要知道她刚刚跟我分手了
Well, you should know that she recently broke up with me.
我说我需要时间思考
I said I needed time to think.
我相信你们俩会想出解决办法
I'm sure you guys will figure something out.
听见了没  拉杰都悲痛欲绝了
You hear that? Raj is devastated.
谢尔顿  别吵  婚礼开始了
Sheldon, shh. The wedding's starting.
我知道怎么回事了
I see what's happening.
大伙儿开始分边站了
Sides are forming.
如果伯纳黛特支持艾米  那我选霍华德好了
Well, if Bernadette's on Amy's team, I pick Howard.
我不偏袒任何一方
I'm not taking sides.
好吧  那我只能选拉杰了
Fine, I guess I'm stuck with Raj.
你不是吧
Really?
至少你被选上了
At least you got picked.
在我继续仪式前
Before I go any further,
我想问你们俩有准备誓词吗
have either of you prepared your own vows?
-有  -没有
- Yes. - No.
你居然写了誓词
You wrote vows?
是的
Yeah.
我一个字都没写
Well, I don't have any.
你让我好没面子啊
You're kind of making me look bad.
没事  我也不一定非要念
It's okay. I-I don't have to say them.
不不不  念吧
No, no, no, go ahead.
我会想出一些伤感的话弄哭你
I'll come up with something mushy, you'll cry,
这很好办
we got this.
"佩妮  粒子从宇宙诞生之初
"Penny, we are made of particles
就存在世上  是它们造就了我们
that have existed since the moment the universe began.
我常想那些原子
I like to think those atoms traveled
用140亿年穿越时间和空间来创造我们
14 billion years through time and space to create us,
好让我们能相遇  完整对方"
so that we could be together and make each other whole."
佩妮
Penny?
好  到我了
Right. Um... okay.
莱纳德  你不仅仅是我一生的挚爱
Leonard, I mean, you're not only the love of my life.
你是我最好的朋友
I mean, you're my best friend, and...
我是你的好朋友
...you've got a friend in me.
你有麻烦
You got troubles.
我做你参谋
I got 'em, too.
为了你我愿意赴汤蹈火
There isn't anything I wouldn't do for you.
我们团结一心  克服所有困难
We stick together, and we can see it through,
因为  我是你的好朋友
'cause... you've got a friend in me.
这不是《玩具总动员》的歌吗
Is that the song from Toy Story?
他可喜欢那部电影了
He loves that movie.
真的
I do.
-真是太美了  -是呀
- Aw, that was beautiful. - Yeah.
虽然没有我们的婚礼美
I mean, not like our wedding beautiful.
当然  我们完胜
No, we totally won.
艾米  我不明白  我们到底分手了没
Amy, I don't understand, are we broken up or not?
你好像一直作不了决定啊
It's like you can't make up your mind.
那是因为你完全不给我思考的空间
It's because you're not giving me any space to think.
是吗  那你最好赶紧想
Well, you should think fast,
因为男人一辈子都能传宗接代
because men can sire offspring their entire lives,
你的卵子可是会过期作废哦
but those eggs you're toting around have a sell-by date.
谢尔顿  你这临门一脚来得正是时候
You know what, Sheldon, you've made this really easy.
你是个幼稚透顶  自私自利的人
You're immature, you're selfish,
你还当面羞辱我
you just insulted me to my face.
我不用再想了  咱俩玩完了
I don't need any more time to think. We're broken up.
艾米
Amy...
有谁能送我回家吗
Will someone take me home?
好吧  我送你回去
Yeah. Come on, I'll give you a ride.
...象征你们永恒的爱
...symbolizes your eternal love.
我现在宣布你们正式结为夫妻
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
我们结婚啦
We did it!
真开心你们能见证这一刻
I'm so glad you guys could watch!
我们就在留言区留"太美太感人"好了
We'll say it was beautiful in the comment section.
不  不  等一下
No, no, no. Hang on.
照习俗我应该抱你入洞房
I believe I'm supposed to carry you across the threshold.
你行吗
Can you?
你以为谢尔顿看电视睡着
Who do you think carries Sheldon to bed
都是哪位壮士抱他回房间的啊
when he falls asleep in front of the TV?
好吧  来吧
Okay, let's do it.
-你能做到吗  -没问题
- You gonna make it? - I'm okay!
顺利完成
Nicely done!
谢谢你
Thank you.
总算有一位"霍夫斯塔德夫人"
Finally, there's a Mrs. Hofstadter
没对我失望了
who isn't disappointed in me.
说这话还为时尚早呢
Well, the night is still young.
你没事吧
Everything all right?
没事
Yeah. I guess.
告诉我嘛
Just tell me.
我们接吻时
It's just, when we were kissing,
我总是忍不住去想你和其他女孩的画面
I couldn't help but picture you with that other girl.
不会吧
Oh, no.
别这样
No, come on.
你可是我的好朋友
I have a friend in you.
你自己说的
You said so.
你说得对  忘掉这事吧
You're right. Just forget it.
好的
Yeah.
好了  听我说
Okay, listen. Uh...
如果你以为那是很香艳的画面
If you're imagining that it was sexy,
其实并没有
it wasn't.
我们都喝挂了  她一股子烟灰缸味
We-we were both drunk, and she smelled like an ashtray.
船身摇晃不定  我还撞碎了她的牙齿
The boat was moving a lot, so I chipped her tooth.
你觉得内疚吗
Did you feel guilty?
不  她有牙医保险
No, she had dental insurance.
你和她接吻后觉得内疚吗
Did you feel guilty after kissing her?
当然  我刚亲完就后悔了
Yes. I felt guilty as soon as it happened.
每次看到她都有深深的负罪感
I feel guilty every time I see her.
你说每次看到她是什么意思
What do you mean, every time you see her?
我...是什么意思呢
What... do I mean?
老天  这个问题可真难
Boy, that's a toughie.
你现在还会见她吗
You still see her?
不  不是约她见面的那种
Well, no, not socially.
只是工作时会遇到
But, you know, just at work.
你还和她一起工作吗
You work with her?!
你怎么不告诉我这件事
How could you not tell me that?!
我在车里就想告诉你  可你要我闭嘴
I wanted to tell you in the car, but you told me to stop talking!
好呀  所以现在是我错了吗
Oh, okay. So you're saying this is my fault?
不  当然不是
No, of course not.
好了  我说
Okay, l-look,
我们不要吵了
instead of fighting,
不如把灯关掉
why don't we dim the lights,
脱光光  造宝宝好不好
um, get naked and make a baby?
我是在努力调节气氛
I was trying to lighten the mood.
这事可不容易  不信你试试
It's not easy. You try it.
妈妈  你好
Hello, Mother.
谢利  宝贝你还好吗
Shelly! How's my baby doing?
我想让你知道
I just wanted to let you know
你可以把艾米从你的夜祷名单上去掉了
that you can remove Amy from your nightly prayers.
除非你愿意祈祷
Unless you're open to praying for
一个大蜂巢掉在她头上
a beehive to fall on her head.
这是怎么了
Oh, what's going on?
她和我分手了
She broke up with me.
谢利
Oh, Shelly.
不  我没事
No, I'll be okay.
但我想把
But I think that I'd like
戒指寄还给你
to send the ring back to you.
先别这么着急
Well, let's not be hasty.
你确定真的结束了吗
Are you sure it's over for good?
反正我是结束了  我受够女人了
It's over for me. I'm done with women.
就像我再也不吃跳跳糖一样
Like when I swore off Pop Rocks.
他们都故意伤害我
They both hurt you on purpose.
想跟妈妈倾诉一下吗
You want to tell me what happened?
你会说一切都是上帝安排好的吗
Are you going to say it's all part of God's plan?
很有可能
Good chance.
谢谢  那还是算了
Then no, thank you.
宝贝  先别把戒指寄回来
Well, honey, don't send it back yet.
你姐姐结婚了  我祖母的戒指
Your sister's married, and I'm not letting your brother
我不想送给你哥哥在泡的那个小荡妇
give my grandmother's ring to that whore he's dating.
抹大拉的玛利亚不也是个妓女吗
Wasn't Mary Magdalene a woman of ill repute?
如果你那白痴哥哥可以拯救人间苍生
When your idiot brother redeems mankind,
那他想和谁约会都没问题
he can date whoever he wants.
我知道你现在很难过  但会过去的
I know it hurts now, but it's gonna get better.
是的
Yeah.
一切都会好起来
Everything's gonna be okay.
你集无数优点于一身
You've got so much to offer.
谢谢你
Thank you.
能和你在一起是每个男人的荣幸
Any man would be lucky to have you.
没错
That's true.
我只希望我做了正确的选择
I just hope I did the right thing.
我肯定你做得对
I'm sure you did.
或许这就是你的问题  永远做正确的选择
Maybe that's the problem-- you always do the right thing.
或许是时候"犯个错误"了
Maybe it's time to do the wrong thing.
比如做你现在这样的错事吗
Like you're doing right now?
没错
Exactly.
我一次又一次问你介不介意
I asked you over and over if you were okay.
如果你介意  为什么还要完婚呢
Why would you go through with the wedding if you weren't?
我本来以为我不介意  谁知道原来不行
I thought I was okay, but it turns out I'm not.
好吧  我或许不是百分百诚实
Okay, listen, I may not have been entirely faithful,
但你体重也不是多轻好吗
but you, you are not easy to lift!
婚姻太适合你了
Well, marriage must agree with you.
你整个人容光焕发啊
Well, you are just glowing.
我才没有容光焕发
I'm not glowing.
我是不爽到炸
I'm upset.
随便你什么心情  反正太适合你了
Well, whatever it is, it agrees with you.
敲  敲  敲  佩妮
Knock, knock, knock, Penny?
这是什么
What's this?
莱纳德都跟我说了
Leonard told me what happened,
所以我自发为你做了热饮
so I took it upon myself to make you a hot beverage.
你真是太贴心了
Oh. That's so sweet of you.
我知道
Yeah. I know.
事实证明  这年头
Turns out, being sweet
贴心并不能留住姑娘
isn't enough to keep a girl these days.
都怪麦当娜
I blame Madonna.
很遗憾你和艾米分手了
I'm sorry to hear about you and Amy.
我也很遗憾莱纳德那样对你
Well, I'm sorry about Leonard.
都怪我没教好他
Thought I raised him better than that.
发生那种事已经够糟心了
You know, it's bad enough what happened,
但更糟心的是他还试图隐瞒
but then he tried to hide the fact that he sees her
他整天能在大学里见到她
all the time at the university.
是吗  谁啊
He does? Who is it?
一个叫曼蒂的女人
Some girl named Mandy.
-曼蒂·周吗  -对的
- Mandy Chao? - Yeah.
你完全不需要担心她
Oh, you don't need to worry about her.
她美貌与智慧兼具
She's brilliant and attractive.
她能找到比莱纳德好十万倍的男人
She can do way better than Leonard.
太好了
That's great.
等等
Wait a minute.
我知道这话可能有点不现实
I know this may sound farfetched,
但我现在也单身了
but I'm on the market now.
如果我跟曼蒂好上了
You know, if I dated Mandy,
应该能给莱纳德与艾米一个教训
that would teach both Leonard and Amy a lesson.
这也太荒谬了
That's ridiculous.
也是
Oh, you're right.
我决不会跟一个自尊心低到能跟莱纳德
I could never be with a woman whose self-esteem was so low
在一起的女人好上
she'd be with Leonard.
我就跟莱纳德在一起啊
I'm with Leonard.
是啊  一辈子呢
Yeah, I know. Forever.
谁敢相信我们居然会碰到这样的事
Who would have believed these things would happen to us?
对吧
Right?
我也不敢相信艾米居然真决定狠下心
I can't believe Amy actually went through with it.
等等
Hang on.
你之前就知道她会跟我分手吗
You knew that she was going to end it with me?
你有试图阻止她吗
Did you try and stop her?
我让她直面本心
I told her to be true to herself
做让自己开心的选择
and do what makes her happy.
Do what makes her happy?
她有竖琴有车
She plays the harp and her car is paid for.
这还不够开心吗
How much happier can she be?
这不能怪我啊
Okay, look, it's not my fault
她是自己觉得你是差劲的男友
that she thought you were a bad boyfriend.
我懂了
I see.
我先走一步了
I think I'll be going.
-谢尔顿  -多说无益
- Sheldon... - No, no, no, no.
就此别过
We are done here.
不介意帮我开个门
Would you mind opening the door
等我出去后  再帮我气愤地甩门吧
and then angrily slamming it behind me?
-好  -多谢
- Sure. - Thank you.
要重重地甩
And slam it hard,
因为我火冒好几丈了
because I am pretty steamed.
好  莱纳德  撑着点啊
All right, Leonard, hang in there.
明天见
Talk to you tomorrow.
怎么了  他们才刚刚完婚不是吗
What happened? They just got married.
我也不知道 反正就一团乱
I don't know. It's a mess.
他们在赌城吵了一大架
They had a huge fight in Vegas.
你觉得他们会分手吗
Think they'll break up?
不确定  听起来挺严重
I don't know. Sounds pretty bad.
佩妮自己一个人在公寓里待着
Penny's back in her apartment all by herself.
是咩
Really?
还想再听另一个
Would you like to hear another reason
为什么男人比女人强的理由吗
why men are better than women?
行啊  说一百个也无妨
Sure, let's make it an even hundred.
你永远不会亲我  让我说"我爱你"
You would never kiss me and make me say "I love you"
然后再跟我分手
and then break up with me.
我的确不会
I wouldn't.
你知道为什么吗
And you know why?
因为你是个男人
'Cause you're a man.
高档牛逼的性别
The champagne of genders.
或许我是个男人
Well, I may be a man,
但这一次做错事的好像是我
but I think I'm the one that screwed up on this one.
是啊  但你像个男人一样  承认了
Yeah, well, and you admit it, like a man.
你只会听到女人说
All you hear women say is,
"我想要一份色拉"
"I'll just have a salad."
"我的唇彩跑哪去了"
"Where's my lip gloss?"
"我觉得这个元素应该叫镭"
"I think this element should be called radium."
最后那句话是居里夫人说的
That last one was Madame Curie.
我想到了
I figured that out.
她其实应该算是荣誉男人
You know what? She was kind of an honorary man.
她有科学做的鸡鸡
She had a penis made of science.
真不敢相信我的新婚之夜是跟你过
Can't believe I'm spending my wedding night with you.
是吗
Really?
我从没想过会有别种可能
I never imagined it any other way.